# **Oscar Forner Martinez**

I am a software engineer with experience in all phases of the development process. I have experience in a diversity of projects ranging from a RESTful API, and compilers to video processing pipelines.

You can use an interactive version of my CV by running: docker run -it maitesin/resume

# **Experience**

#### 2018-Present Senior Backend Software Engineer at GlobalSign

As part of my duties in GlobalSign I implemented new functionalities in the **High Performance Platform** that serve thousands of certificates per second, and I took care of the migration of backend storage from **MongoDB** to **PostgreSQL**.

Moreover, implemented a prototype of the system used in production running in **Kubernetes** to test the feasibility of a future migration.

I mentored multiple new-hires and had a highly involved role in the hiring process.

#### 2016-2018 Software Engineer at VCA Technology

During my time at VCA Technology I created a **network library** that allows the user to interact with **Boost ASIO** through the **std::stream** interface, added **authentication** to the system, and designed the **configuration migration process**.

In addition, I improved the in-house **toolchain** to use **clang-tidy** for the linting of our code and I lead the usage of **continuous integration** in order to improve the product delivered to the customer, and to reduce the time to market.

#### 2015-2016 Software Developer at Programming Research

I worked in two projects during my time at Programming Research.

- -Static analysis of code: Checks if the code has some patterns that have an undefined behaviour, unspecified in the Standard, and/or implementation-defined.
- -Dataflow analysis of code: Checks the complexity of methods, pointer problems, memory handling, etc.

## 2013-2015 Software Engineer at European Bioinformatics Institute

One of my duties was to create a RESTful service to allow users to query for information about multiprotein complexes.

In addition, I developed an algorithm to cluster biological information from proteins.

## **Education**

**2010-2013** Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science; Universitat Jaume I (Spain)

Advanced Data Structures, Compilers and Interpreters and Distributed Systems

**2006-2010** Associate Degree in Computer Science; Universitat Jaume I (Spain)

Operating Systems, Real Time Operating Systems and Embedded Systems

# **Programming Languages**

C++ 5 years of experience using *Modern C*++ and *Boost*.

**Python** 5 years of experience.

**C** 4 years of experience.

**Go** 3 year of experience.

### Technical Skills

Build CMake, Meson, Make and Ninja.

CI GitLab-CI, Jenkins, Bamboo and Travis.

Databases MongoDB, PostgreSQL, CockroachDB, MariaDB, SQLite and MySQL.

Analysis Clang-sanitizer, Coverity, Perf and Valgrind.

Orchestra- Kubernetes and Docker compose.

tion

Message Bro- RabbitMQ and Kafka.

ker

Operating

g GNU/Linux, MacOS, FreeBSD and OpenBSD.

Systems

Languages

Spanish Native

**English** Fluent

oscar.forner.martinez@gmail.com +44 (0)75 96944383

Blog: https://oscarforner.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/oscarforner

GitHub: https://github.com/maitesin